Welcome to Saturday Enrichment here at Bodwell
BodwellのSaturday Enrichmentプログラムへようこそ
Also known as "E-Block" or "Saturday E".
このプログラムは、”Eブロック”もしくは”土曜日E”ともよばれています
This is an opportunity for students to wake up
１学期中の土曜日に10回行われるプログラムで
on Saturday mornings 10 times in a term.
週末に生活リズムが大きく崩れない為にも行われています。
have classes for 3 hours with instructors from the community or here at the school
学生達は、特別なインストラクター、もしくはBodwellの教師たちから
in a wide variety of topics and skill areas.
様々なトピックとスキル上達の為の、３時間のクラスを受講します。
Why do we do Saturday E?
Why do we do Saturday E? Saturday Enrichmentプログラムの意義
We do it for a number of reasons, one of the reasons is
一つ目の理由は
it helps students to improve their English
学生の英語上達の機会を更に設けるためです。
and it gives them more time to practice and use English in different contexts
土曜のプログラムで、生徒達に更に、英語を学習、練習する時間を与える事ができます。
Other reasons include: we want students to
他の理由としては、色々な土曜日クラスの科目を通し
spend more time to explore different passions,
将来を職業やゴールを考える機会を与え、
career options, different skills
自分が情熱を傾けることができるもの 、新しいものへの興味、
and different areas of pursuits in life.
スキルセットの探求の機会を持ってもらうためです
It helps them stand out on their university applications with a lot more experience
ボドウェルの土曜日プログラムで得た、知識や経験は、大学への入試の際にも役に立ちます。
It helps them have connections to the community
また、地域とのつながりをより強く持ってもらうことも、このプログラムを行っている理由の一つです
through doing field trips and meeting different interesting guest speakers,
社会見学、様々な分野で活躍している人とのふれあいを通し、学生達が実際の社会に触れることによって、
It helps them get real world knowledge about different careers
今まで知らなかった分野への知識、世界で何が起こっているのかを肌で感じ、垣間見ることもできます。
different interesting things that are happening in the world
その様な経験が、キャリアゴールの設定にも役に立つと考えています。
and finally, it allows students to make good use of their weekend time
また、土曜日プログラムを通じ、通常では経験できない事を、
for real learning in a unique setting.
体験する事で、週末を有意義に過ごしてもらう事も目的です。
Each term the students have the opportunity to choose
毎学期、学生は自分の英語レベル、学年に沿ったクラスを
from a wide variety of classes depending on their English and grade level.
選択することができます。
for students in the younger grades and beginner level English,
低学年の学生、英語のレベルが低い学生の為、
we have opportunities for them is classes such as
学生が興味がある項目、例えば、旅行・観光、
English For Life,  Travel and Tourism, Crafts and Cultures
クラフトとカルチャーなどをトピックとし、
We blend English learning with other topics and interesting content
日常英語を学んでもらう機会も設けています。
For students in the senior grades and with stronger English
高学年の学生、英語レベルが高い生徒たちのためには
we have much more challenging courses in the areas of
スポーツ、工学、コンピューターサイエンスや
Sports and Beyond, Engineering, Computer Science, and Electronic Music IESTS test prep.
コンピューターでの作曲や、IELTSテスト準備などの高度な内容のクラスを用意しています。
English 12 support and many, many other courses
英語１２補修コースなども設けています。
Students often find that we  add new and innovative courses each term
毎学期、生徒のニーズに基づいて、新しく、実用的なコースが変更・追加されます。
And we try to have a wide variety of themes
ビジネス分野から、アウトドア、スポーツ、社会科学分野、ボランティア活動、その他など、
from business to outdoors, athletics, citizenship, volunteering, careers and many other areas as well
様々な分野への学生の興味を刺激するよう工夫されています。
From what I 've experienced students don't mind coming into school Saturday morning
そして、土曜日プログラムは、
they actually enjoy the opportunity to get to know people with similar interests
同じ分野への興味を持つ生徒と知り合い、
who share their interests
探求できる仲間を見つける機会となるため
and they have the opportunity to explore those interests together
とても有意義な場所となっていると、生徒達からもフィードバックを受けています。
They really love the opportunity to meet mentors and professionals in their fields of interest
また、学生は興味のある分野の専門家に会う機会を持つことができ、
and they have a lot of fun in the process
彼らの経験から多くの事を学びます。
The benefits are very clear.
その効果は言うまでもなく明確です。
Students will gain more confidence, more passion, curiosity
学生達は、土曜日プログラムを通じ、自信、興味、好奇心を高め
and more well-roundedness.through this program
色々な知識の幅を広げる事ができます。
I expect students to put in a lot of time and commitment and energy
私は学生達が、多くの時間とエネルギーを注ぎ、プログラムに専念することを期待しています。
In the end the will receive a lot of benefit through this unique opportunity here at Bodwell.
また、Bodwellが提供するユニークなプログラムから、できるだけ沢山の事を学んでもらいたいと願っています。